Hurry up!
The flight leaves in four hours!
네 시간밖에 안 남았는데 뭐해
길 막히면 택시 잡기도 힘들어
There could be traffic!
The plane could leave early!
비행기 일찍 뜨면 어떡하니
런던도 북새통일 거야, 빨랑!
In London, there could be
a line at customs! Come on!
Six-hour trip to London.
That's a lot of Monica.
런던까지는 여섯 시간
견디기 좀 힘들겠다
What have you got there?
그건 뭐지?
Condoms, dude.
콘돔이지 뭐야
Well, how come the writing is in spanish?
근데 웬 스페인어?
Don't read my condoms.
내 콘돔 읽지 마
Passport, check. Camera, check.
Traveler's checks, check.
여권 확인, 카메라 확인
여행자수표 확인
-Who are you saying "check" to?
-Myself.
누굴 확인시키는데?
나, 빠짐없이 챙겨야지
For remembering to pack a thing.
You do a good thing,
you get a "check."
착한 일을 해도 확인!
Mom does it.
I never realized it was weird.
우리 엄마도 그러셨어
그게 뭐 이상하니?
My mom used to put her head
in the oven.
우리 엄만 오븐에
머리를 집어넣곤 했어
Actually, only the one time.
But it's pretty weird.
아, 딱 한 번이었구나
그래도 진짜 이상하더라
- 얘들아
- 어서 와
Are you ready yet?
- 짐 다 꾸렸니?
- 그래, 티켓 챙겼어?
-Got the tickets?
-Right here. Check!
여기 넣었지, 확인!
It's all London, baby!
런던아 기다려라
우리가 간다
Here we go.
Got your passport?
여권 있어?
그래, 세 번째 서랍에
잃어버리면 안 되잖아
Third drawer of my dresser.
You don't want to lose that!
감 잡았냐?
There it is!
The One With Ross' Wedding
진공청소기는
내 옷장 왼쪽에 있고
The vacuum's in my closet
on the left side.
쓰레기봉투는 냉장고 옆에
Garbage bags are next
to the refrigerator.
레이첼도 남을 건데
걔한테 시키면 안돼?
Rachel's gonna be here.
Can't I just ask her?
해봐, 잘될지 모르지만
Yeah, okay. Give that a try!
-Let's do it.
-Cheerio!
- 자, 출발이다
- 야호
London, baby!
런던이다, 짜샤
That's not gonna get annoying.
점점 듣기 좋아진다
런던이다, 짜샤
London, baby!
You know what?
I was wrong.
그래, 내가 잘못했어
We're all here.
Let's get going!
다 모였으니까
출발해야겠다
I want to go over and hug you...
식 잘 올리라고 안아주면
좋겠지만 못 일어나겠네
...and wish you luck,
but I can't get up.
-I'll come hug you.
-Great, can you bring me the paper?
- 내가 안아줄게
- 그럼 신문 좀 가져와
그래
-Have a great wedding.
-Thanks.
식 잘 올려
고마워
Chandler, I want to hug you too!
챈들러, 너도 안고 싶어
You might as well bring my book
from your apartment.
너희 아파트에 있는
내 책 좀 갖다 줄래?
이제 우리 간다
-So we're off.
-Have fun!
- 잘하고 와
- 고마워
-I can't believe you won't be there.
-I know.
- 못 간다니 너무 서운하다
- 알아
Come. Why don't you come?
너도 가면 좋잖아
뭐가
To London. Please?
It would mean so much to me.
런던에 함께 가자
네가 빠지면 되니?
일 때문에 그래, 미안해
I gotta work. I'm sorry.
며칠 휴가 내면 되잖아
Why can't you take
a couple of days off?
그건 곤란하다니까
벌써 얘기했잖아
Because I can't.
I told you.
This is my wedding.
내 결혼식이야
이젠 정말 늦었다
얼른 가! 빨랑 가!
Now we are late.
Let's go, let's go!
Fine, you'll watch it
on video when we get back.
그래, 비디오로 담아올게
Here you go, Phoebe!
Phoe-bo! Phoo-ba-la!
여기 있다, 피비
포보, 푸불라, 파베부
고맙다
You!
녀석...
Let's go!
좋아, 가자
잘 있어, 피비
Bye, Pheebs!
갔다 올게
잘 다녀와
안녕
런던이다, 짜샤!
London, baby!
Oh, God!
Do you need a hug?
내가 안아줄까?
심부름 안 시킬게
You don't have to bring me anything.
런던 메리어트 호텔
Chandler, do something!
챈들러, 뭐든 해봐
-Do something!
-I am. I'm ignoring you.
뭐든 해보라니까
널 무시하고 있잖아
받아, 이젠 내가 찍힐래
I'll be the on-camera guy.
All right. First stop...
좋아, 첫 번째 방문지는
웨스트민스터 성당
...Westminster Abbey.
What is that?
그건 또 뭡니까?
런던이잖아, 짜샤
That's London, baby!
All right, the hotel's here.
좋아, 호텔은 여기고...
Wait.
잠깐
We want to go
아니, 저쪽이...
아닌데
알았다
I know.
I'm gonna have to go into the map.
지도 안으로 들어가자
If you see a little version
of me in there, kill it!
거기서 조그만 날
만나면 죽여 버려
I got it.
알았어
이쪽이야
Here we go!
We're not gonna have to walk this way
the entire time, are we?
계속 이런 식으로
걸을 건 아니지?
Man, you made me lose it!
또 헷갈렸잖아
That was all before 10:00.
그게 10시 전이었어
The caterer rang. It'll be Chicken
Kiev, not Tarragon.
치킨 타라곤은 안 되고
치킨 키에브만 된대
Then the florist said
there are no tulips.
게다가 튤립도 없다는 거야
또 첼리스트는 팔목에
이상이 생겼다나 뭐라나...
And the cellist has
carpal tunnel syndrome
에밀리, 자기야, 됐지?
Emily, honey. Okay?
Well, up yours too!
자기도 엿 먹어
-What?
-Oh, that's not what it means.
뭐?
그런 뜻이 아니었어?
아니, 타임아웃이라고
-No! That's "time out."
-Sorry.
미안해
마음 좀 가라앉혀
다 잘될 거야
Sweetie, relax.
Everything will be great, okay?
이러지 마
Come on, come on.
치킨 키에브?
Chicken Kiev?
먹음직스런 이름이잖아?
Doesn't that sound delicious
at the last minute?
그렇지만 치킨보다는
연어가 품위 있을 텐데
Salmon would be
more elegant than chicken.
And you wouldn't worry
about the salmonella.
살모넬라 걱정도 없고
물론 연어로 한다면
'치키넬라'가 문제지
But of course...
...with salmon you would have
to worry about the chicknella.
식장 빨리 보고 싶다
I can't wait to see
where you're getting married.
그래, 에밀리 부모님도 식을
올린 곳인데 정말 아름다워
It's beautiful.
Her parents got married here.
I can't believe
they're tearing it down.
그런 걸 왜 허는지 몰라요
얼마나 예쁜 건물이라구요
It's really the most lovely building.
It's over
바로 저기...
Oh, my God!
맙소사
It's nice.
멋지네요
세상에
Oh, my God!
이게 무슨 일이야
우린 어떡하지?
What are we going to do?
Everything's gonna be all right.
괜찮아, 잘될 거야
상황이 이런데 어떻게 잘돼
How's it gonna be all right?
어허, 그러게
I see that.
인부한테 자초지종을 들었어
I talked to a guy,
and I found out what happened.
뭐래
며칠 일찍 철거한대요
They tore it down early.
All right!
그렇지, 웨스트민스터 성당!
Westminster Abbey.
Hands down, best abbey I ever seen.
두말이 필요 없어
내가 본 성당 중 최고다
야
좋습니다, 이 성당을
어떻게 생각하시죠?
What do you think of the Abbey?
It's great! They're thinking
of changing the name.
그래, 아주 좋긴 한데
성당 이름을 바꾼다더라
- 진짜? 뭘로?
- '카메라 치워'로
-To what?
-To "Put the Camera Away"!
Man, you are Westminster Crabby.
넌 웨스트민스터 투덜이다
Don't worry, you'll find
some place to get married.
다른 장소가 있을 거예요
Sorry. Lucky this dress is red.
미안해요, 다행히
빨간 드레스네요
We can't find another place.
다른 데는 없어요
Then we can't have the wedding.
그럼 식도 못 올리고
치킨에다 샐러드, 케이크까지
150명분이나 주문했는데
I've ordered chicken, and salad,
and cake for a 150.
What should be the most wonderfull day
of my life...
내 생애 최고의 날이 음식만
잔뜩 쌓인 일요일로 변하겠네
...is rapidly turning into just Sunday
with a spectacular amount of food.
You're gonna find a place.
식장은 찾을 수 있어요
But even if, God forbid, you didn't,
so you postpone the wedding.
하지만 설사 못 찾는다 해도
식을 좀 연기하면 되잖아요
Is that really so bad?
원하는 대로 차분히 준비할
시간을 버니까 오히려 좋죠
Think about it. You could take all the time
your needed to get everything that you want.
튤립도 준비하고
연어도 준비하고
You could have tulips.
You could have salmon.
음... 연어
Salmon.
I suppose it wouldn't be
the end of the world.
맞아요, 세상이 끝난 건 아니죠
고마워요
Oh, thank you.
어쨌든 결혼하고 나면 엄마는
나보다 올케를 좋아할 거예요
Look, either way you're gonna get married.
You're gonna be happy.
My mom's gonna like you better than me.
Oh, God. She has told you
that already, didn't she?
맙소사, 엄마가 벌써
그렇게 얘기했군요
얘, 일어나지 마
뭐가 필요하니?
-Don't get up. What do you need?
-Nothing.
아냐, 됐어
내가 왜 남았는데
필요한 거 있음 말해
Come on. I'm here
to take care of you.
Okay, I have a wedgie.
엉덩이에 옷이 끼었어
That is all you.
네가 그렇지 뭐
점심은 뭘로 할까
What do you want for lunch?
I don't know.
글쎄다
I guess we have to eat.
먹긴 먹어야겠지
난 먹어야 돼
Yeah, I do.
What's the matter?
왜 그래?
I'm bummed the way
I left things with Ross.
로스한테 말을 잘못했어
I wish I didn't lie about work.
He seemed so mad at me.
바쁘다고 했더니
많이 서운했나 봐
너무 자책하지 마, 아직
사랑하는 감정이 있는데...
Don't be so hard on yourself.
If I was still in love with some
사랑하는 감정?
Still in love with?
그래
I'm not in love with Ross.
난 로스 사랑하지 않아
오...
아냐, 잘됐다
Good!
Yeah, me neither.
나도 그러니까
I'm not at the wedding,
because he's my ex-boyfriend...
옛날 남자친구 결혼식에
가면 마음이 편하겠니?
...and that would be uncomfortable.
사랑은 무슨 사랑이야
Not because I'm in love with him.
I like Ross as much as anyone.
기본적인 호감 정도는 있지
Clearly, I have feelings for him,
but they don't mean love.
물론 감정은 남았지만
그게 사랑은 아냐
I mean, do I still have
loving feelings for Ross? Yeah!
아직 사랑의 감정이
남아있을까?
그래!
사랑의 감정이 남았다고
사랑하고 있는 건 아냐
I have continuing feelings of love.
But that doesn't mean
I'm still in love with him.
성적인 감정은 있지만
난 로스를 사랑해
I have sexual feelings for him,
but I do love him.
Oh, my God!
맙소사
Why didn't you tell me?
왜 얘기 안 해줬어!
-We thought you knew!
-We?
우린 네가 아는 줄 알았지
우리?
그래, 우린 맨날
그 얘기만 했거든
We all know.
We talk about it all the time.
You all know?
Does Ross know?
너희가 알면
로스도 알아?
아냐, 로스가 뭘 알아
No! Ross doesn't know anything.
And you didn't tell me!
그 얘길 안 해주면 어떡해
한눈에 봐도 뻔한 걸
꼭 말로 해야 되니?
We thought you knew.
It's so obvious!
모니카한테 이렇게 물어보리?
'너 깨끗한 거 좋아하지?'
It would be like telling Monica:
"Hey, you like things clean."
아니면 '조이, 넌 게이야'
Or, you know, "Hey, Joey, you're gay."
What?
뭐?
이거 왜 이래, 모니카는
빗자루를 들고 살잖아
Oh, please, she's always got
a broom in her hand.
안녕하세요
뭘 찾으십니까
스카프, 그림엽서...
What are you in the market for?
Scarves, souvenir postcards....
Check this out!
이걸 봐
오호라, 죽인다
That's the stuff!
What do you think?
어때?
I won't need that
"I'm with stupid" T-shirt anymore.
'난 푼수다'라고 박힌
티셔츠는 필요 없겠네
Well, I like it. Here you go.
난 맘에 들어
여기 있어요
제발 이러지 마라
더 이상 얼굴 팔리기 싫다
You're not really buying that.
Haven't you embarrassed me enough?
나 땜에 얼굴 팔리냐?
Oh, I embarrass you?
How can I answer when
I'm pretending I don't know you?
우린 모르는 사이니까
말 걸지 마라
He's just jealous.
All Londoners wear them.
런던사람들은 모두
그걸 쓴답니다
그래요? 그럼 왜
한 사람도 안 보이죠?
Really? Then how come no one here
anywhere is wearing one?
They're all tourists.
다 관광객들이니까
If you insist on wearing that
in public...
꼭 그걸 써야겠다면
지금부터 너 혼자 다녀라
...you're gonna spend the afternoon
all by yourself.
그래?
If you make me choose between
you and the hat, I choose the hat.
너랑 모자 중에 고르라면
난 모자를 선택하겠어
- 현명한 선택이오
- 고마워요
-Good choice.
-Thanks.
이거 봐
됐어, 난 이쯤해서 빠질게
더 이상 창피 당하기 싫어
That's it! I'm out of here.
I won't be embarrassed any more.
안녕하세요, 미국에서 온
조이 트리비아니입니다
How are you doing? Joey Tribbiani, America.
나 왔어
그래, 방금 장인어른이랑
통화했는데...
I spoke to your dad,
and you know what?
괜찮은 식장을 봐두셨나 봐
He thinks we can find a new hall.
-We don't have to.
-You found a place?
그럴 필요 없어
왜, 자기가 찾았어?
No, but Monica and I were talking...
그건 아니지만
모니카랑 얘기했는데...
...and I was so upset about the hall
being knocked down...
내가 식장 때문에
속상해하니까
식을 연기하는 게
어떠냐는 거야
...and she suggested we put
the wedding off for a bit.
She said what?
뭐랬다고?
마음에 드는 식장이 없으면
조금 연기하는 것도 좋잖아
If I won't be happy with somewhere
we'd find in a day...
...we should postpone it.
Postpone it.
연기한다고?
이번 일로 양가의 출혈이
얼마나 컸는지 걔가 알까?
Do you think Monica realizes
how much our parents spent on this?
그 새머리통으로 이해될까?
Do you think my sister's teeny,
tiny, little brain comprehends...
...that people took time
out of their lives...
자기 시간 죽여 가며 천리만리
날아오는 하객들의 심정을?
...to fly thousands of miles
to be here?
This isn't right.
이건 아냐
I realize that people
are gonna be disappointed.
물론 사람들 실망이 크겠지만
제대로 준비해서
모시면 더 좋잖아
But I'm sure they'll come back.
난 그런 얘기 못해
자기는 할 수 있어?
I can't ask people to do that.
Would you?
Don't you point your pants at me!
어따 바지로 삿대질이야
We have no choice.
다른 수가 없잖아
Anywhere half-decent
will have been booked.
웬만한 데는 다 예약이 끝났고
모르겠어? 우리의 결혼식이야
Don't you understand?
This is our wedding!
아무튼 연기는 생각할 수 없어
우린 지금 결혼해야 돼
Postponing it is not an option.
This is when we're getting married.
-You're saying it's now or never?
-I'm saying it's now.
지금 아니면 못하겠다고?
아니, 지금 하자는 거야
아니면?
-Or?
-There's no "or" in mine!
내 사전에 '아니면'은 없어
What is wrong with these pants?
뭔 바지가 이 모양이야!
It's not the pants.
It's you who's backwards.
잘못된 건 바지가 아니라
바로 자기야
If you don't understand
how important this is to me...
내 마음을 그렇게 몰라준다면
아예 식을 취소하는 게 낫겠어
...perhaps we shouldn't marry at all!
아니, 잠깐, 에밀리
자기야, 제발... 아야!
Emily, no! Wait, stop!
Emily, please
왔니?
그래
어때, 쇼핑하니까
기분이 좀 나아졌어?
Did shopping help you
feel any better?
맨해튼에 가게가
이것밖에 없었니?
Manhattan doesn't have enough stores.
로스를 잊도록
내가 도와줄까?
I can help you get over him.
You can?
- 방법이 있어?
- 그래
로스 사진 몇 장하고...
I need you to bring me
photos of Ross...
- 알았어
- 조그만 초콜릿...
...and a small piece of chocolate...
...and a glass of tepid water.
- 좋아
- 미지근한 물 한 잔
Is this where you throw stuff...
오! 무덤의 흙을 주머니에 담아
나무에 매다는 거랑 비슷하네?
...in a bag with graveyard dirt
and hang it from a north-facing tree?
Only if you have the hiccups too.
지금 누가 딸꾹질하니?
초콜릿하고 물은 내 거야
일어나기 싫어서
The chocolate and water are for me.
I didn't feel like getting up.
이제 너한테 로스의
사진을 보여줄 테니까
I'll show you a picture of Ross.
나빴던 기억을 모두 떠올려
로스의 단점을 잘 생각해봐
And you remember all
the bad things about him.
-Focus on his flaws.
-I can do that.
할 수 있어, 한참
사귈 때도 해봤거든
I did that
while we were going out.
좋아
Before we start, I want to say,
for the record, I love Ross.
시작하기 전에 말해두지만
난 로스를 정말 괜찮은
남자라고 생각하거든?
He's such a great guy.
됐어, 이제 눈을 감고...
Close your eyes.
Imagine that you're with Ross.
로스와 함께 있다고 생각해
Imagine that you're kissing him.
키스하는 걸 상상하면서...
You're running your hands
all over his body.
로스의 온몸을 더듬는다
You run your hands
through his hair but
머리칼을 쓸어주는데...
우웩! 끔직해라!
개기름이 질질!
Gross!
It's some kind of grease.
I don't know.
글쎄, 머리카락이
역겨운 적은 없었는데
His hair never bothered me that much.
It was more crunchy
than it was greasy.
오히려 약간 푸석한 편이지
그래, 생각보다 힘들구나
This will be harder than I thought.
Let's try some aversion therapy.
그럼 혐오요법을 써보자
- 좋아
- 됐지?
- 사진을 봐
- 그래
Look at the picture.
자, 이제...
아우!
How do you feel now?
지금 기분은 어때?
글쎄, 네가 싫어진다 얘
Well, I like you less.
이것도 영국만큼 따분하구나
나 왔다
그래
오, 죄송합니다
Sorry.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have said
you were embarrassing me.
아니, 미안한 건 나야
내가 말을 너무 심하게 했어
That wasn't cool.
위로가 될지 모르지만
나 오늘 진짜 따분했다
If it makes you feel any better,
I've had a really lousy day.
Me too.
나도
그래?
-Yeah?
-No!
아냐!
I had the best day ever!
너무 신나는 하루였어
Dude, check this out!
이걸 한번 봐
너랑 찍은 건 빨리 감자
무지하게 지루하니까
- 얘들아
- 쉬쉬쉬!
Tell my friend you like my hat.
제 친구한테 이 모자가
맘에 든다고 말해주세요
- 친구 이름이 뭐죠?
- 챈들러예요
-What's your friend's name?
-Chandler.
Hi, Chandler.
안녕, 챈들러?
-That's
-That's Fergie, baby!
이 여자는...
- 세상에
- 퍼기잖아, 짜샤!
이 모자를 싫어한다던데
내가 볼 땐 너무 근사해요
Joey says you don't like his hat,
but I think it's kind of dashing.
지금 사귀는 사람 없죠?
So I hear you're single now.
그 정도로 근사하진 않아요
- Yeah, I don't like the hat that much.
-Okay.
어떻게... 언제...
When did you?
How?
버킹엄궁전에 가고 싶어서
지도 속에 들어갔지, 근데...
I was trying to get
to Buckingham Palace.
So I'm in my map and
왔니?
- 어서 와
- 그래
I understand you had
a talk with Emily.
에밀리한테 조언을 해줬다며?
Yes, I did.
그랬지
And you are welcome.
고마워할 거 없어
Am l?
그러시와요?
식을 연기하라고 했니?
Was it your idea
to postpone the wedding?
-I'm going to the bathroom.
-Wait up!
- 나 화장실 간다
- 나도!
네가 해결사인 모양인데
질문 한 개만 받아주라
Since you're the fix-it lady,
here's a pickle:
What do you do when the bride says
she doesn't want the wedding at all?
신부가 아예 결혼식을
취소할 경우엔 어떡하지?
She said that?
Why?
- 안 하겠대?
- 그래
- 왜?
- 난들 아니?
I don't know. I said it was stupid
to put off the wedding...
예식장 때문에 결혼을 연기할 순
없다고 했더니 저렇게 나오잖아
...and she, like, flipped out.
내가 못살아, 오빤
나보다 더한 바보야
Oh, my God!
You're even dumber than I am.
Excuse me?
뭐라구요?
How long have you been planning
this wedding?
오빠는 이 결혼
얼마 동안 준비했어?
I don't know. A month?
글쎄, 한 달 정도?
Emily's probably been planning it
since she was 5.
에밀리는 5살 때부터
준비했을 거야
Ever since the first time she hung
a pillowcase from her head.
처음으로 베갯잇 벗겨서
머리에 뒤집어썼을 때부터
그게 여자야
That's what we did.
We dreamed about the perfect wedding.
여자들은 완벽한 결혼식을 꿈꿔
In the perfect place.
완벽한 예식장과...
With the perfect
four-tiered wedding cake.
완벽한 4단 웨딩케이크
With the little people on top.
꼭대기엔 앙증맞은 인형
But the most important part...
하지만 가장 중요한 대목은
완벽한 남자를 만나는 거야
...is that we had the perfect guy...
...who understood just how important
all that stuff was.
이 모든 걸 이해해주는 사람
I had no idea.
난 미처 몰랐다
That pillowcase thing, I thought
you were doing The Flying Nun.
여자애들이 베갯잇 갖고
수녀놀이 하는 줄 알았어
Sometimes we were.
가끔 그럴 때도 있지
Come on.
이리 와
Help me figure out what to do.
오빠 좀 도와줘야겠다
알았어
가자
- 뭔 일 나는 줄 알았네
- 그러게
Pretty intense, huh?
I hope Ross didn't think we left
because we were uncomfortable here.
우리가 불편해서 들어갔다고
생각하면 큰일인데?
I hope he did.
그렇게 생각해야지
이건 엄청 큰 결점이다
로스는 껌으로 풍선을 불어
I thought of a good flaw.
Ross pops his gum.
맞아
Oh, right.
-Wait a minute. I do that too.
-I know, it drives me crazy.
- 잠깐, 나도 그러는데?
- 그것 때문에 나 미치잖아
I'll get it.
내가 받을게
여보세요
Pheebs, it's Joey.
안녕, 피비
나야, 조이
조이, 참! 지하철에서
너랑 닮은 사람 봤는데
Hey, Joey!
I saw someone that looks just
like you on the subway.
I was going to say hi, then I figured
he doesn't care he looks like you.
그 사람은 너 닮은 거 별 관심
없는 듯해서 아는 척 안 했어
That just cost me 4 bucks.
방금 통화료 4달러 나갔다
I called to see how the chick
and the duck are doing.
우리 닭이랑 오리
어떻게 지내나 해서
피비 고모랑 잘 놀고 있어
레이첼 고모는 도움이 안 되고
They're having fun with Aunt Phoebe.
Aunt Rachel hasn't been helpful.
나 보고 싶어?
So do you miss me?
Kind of, but I've been
having too much fun.
그렇긴 한데
여기 너무 재미있다
향수병은 걱정 없겠구나
You're not homesick yet?
I don't think so.
그럼, 당연하지
Well, the seven of us miss you.
우리 일곱은
네가 그리운데
-Who's seven?
-Me, Rachel...
일곱이라니
알잖아, 나, 레이첼
새들, 아기들
...the birds, the babies.
The babies miss me?
아기들도 내가 보고 싶대?
물론이지, 아니면
내가 시장한 건가?
Of course they do, or I'm just really hungry.
피자 왔다
Pizza guy's here!
You ordered pizza without me?
나도 없는데 피자를 시켰어?
But we were thinking about you.
We ordered the Joey Special.
하지만 네 생각하면서
조이 스페셜로 주문했어
Two pizzas?
두 판씩이나?
그래, 끊어야겠다
나중에 얘기하자
-Gotta go! Talk to you later.
-Wait!
잠깐, 어디서 시켰는데
Where did you get it from?
치어스
And they're always glad you came
You want to be where you can see
Your troubles are all the same
You want to be
Where everybody knows your name
여긴 왜 오자고 해요?
Why have you brought me here?
기다려 봐요
You'll see.
This wedding won't happen.
결혼식은 없다고 했잖아요
Ross.
로스...
여기 조명이 더 많이
있다고 생각해봐, 또...
But imagine a lot more lights...
...and fewer bricks...
뭐, 벽돌은 치울 거고...
...and flowers and candles.
꽃과 촛불...
And the musicians can go over here.
악단은 여기 앉을 거예요
좌석은 이쪽으로 배열하고...
The chairs can face this way and
You go.
오빠가 해
But if you don't love this,
we'll do it any other place or time.
여기가 맘에 안 든다면
언제 어디서라도 난 상관없어
Really, it's fine.
Whatever you want.
자기 뜻을 따를게
It's perfect.
이 정도면 완벽해
And, I don't know, if it rains
- 혹시 비가 오면...
- 그럼 맞지 뭐
Then we'll get wet.
I don't even have a date.
난 애인도 없는데
- 피비?
- 그래
Do you remember
where the duck food is?
오리 밥 어디 있는지 알아?
그래, 저쪽 아파트
싱크대 밑에, 왜?
In the guys' apartment,
under the sink. Why?
Because I'm going to London.
런던에 가려고
뭐? 런던엔 뭐 하러
What? What do you mean?
I have to tell Ross I love him.
로스한테 사랑한다고 말할 거야
몸조심하고 내가
돌아올 때까지 애 낳지 마
Take care and don't have
the babies till I get back.
But what about all
the finding-his-flaws stuff we've been doing?
그럼 지금까지 로스
흠집 낸 건 어떡하고
그거 효과 없더라
Yeah, that didn't work.
가지 마, 로스는
에밀리를 사랑해
You can't go.
Ross loves Emily.
그건 나도 알지만
내 감정을 알려야 돼
I know, but I have
to tell him how I feel.
He deserves all the information
to make an informed decision.
다양한 정보가 있어야
현명한 판단을 내리지
You're going
because you hope he'll say:
로스가 이렇게 나오길 바라지?
'널 사랑해, 영국계집은 잊자'
"l love you too.
Forget the British chippy."
You think he will?
그렇게 될까?
No, because he's in love
with the British chippy!
안 되지, 로스는
그 영국계집을 사랑하니까
네가 가면 로스의
결혼식만 망치게 돼
You're just gonna mess with his head
and ruin his wedding.
It's too late!
You missed your chance.
이젠 너무 늦었어
넌 기회를 놓쳤다고
I'm sorry.
This must be hard.
물론 받아들이기 힘들겠지만...
But it's over.
다 끝났어
No, it's not over
until someone says, "l do."
누구든 '네'라고 하기 전엔
끝난 게 아냐
I do! I do!
네! 네! 네! 네!
Like I can really chase you.
I'm carrying a litter!
애 밴 여자가 쫓아가면
얼마나 쫓아간다고
The Waltham residence.
월섬 씨 댁입니다
거기가 에밀리의
부모님 댁인가요?
Is this Emily's parents' house?
This is the housekeeper speaking.
전 가정부입니다만
And, by the way, that is not how one
addresses a person on the telephone.
이런 식으로 사람을 찾는 건
큰 결례라 아니 할 수 없지요
First one identifies oneself...
먼저 본인의 신분을 밝히고
...and then asks for the person
with whom one wishes to speak.
통화할 상대를 바꿔달라는 것이
법도에 맞는 행동이라 하겠지요
What are you saying?
뭔 소리죠?
그럼 다시 한번 실습하지요
Now, let us try that again, shall we?
안돼, 오!
No!
Oh, my God!
기가 막혀서!
-The Waltham residence.
-Hello.
월섬 씨 댁입니다
안녕하세요
전 피비 부페이인데요
This is Phoebe Buffay.
I was wondering, please...
대단히 죄송합니다만...
행여 폐가 안 된다면...
...if it's not
too much trouble, please...
에밀리 월섬 양과
통화가 가능할까요?
...might I speak with
Miss Emily Waltham, please?
Miss Waltham is
at the rehearsal dinner.
월섬 양은 리허설디너에
참석 중이지요
And it is not polite
to make fun of people. Goodbye.
사람을 놀리는 것 또한
예의가 아니지요, 그럼
안돼요! 이제 진짜 잘할게요
그쪽 연락처 좀 알 수 있나요?
I'll be nice, I swear. Could you just
give me the number for where they are?
I'm afraid I'm not at liberty
to divulge that information.
전 그런 걸 알려줄 만한
권한이 없는 사람이지요
누군가 그 결혼식을 망치러
가는 중이라 알려줘야 돼요
Somebody is on their way to ruin
the wedding, and I have to warn somebody.
안 가르쳐주면 당장 쫓아가서
잘난 엉덩짝을 질러버리겠어요
So if you don't give me that number,
I'm gonna come over there...
...and I'm gonna kick your snooty ass
all the way to New Gloukenshire!
Hello? Hello?
여보세요? 우! 진짜로
엉덩이를 까버릴까부다
She knew I could kick her ass.
- 오빠
- 왔구나
-Hi, sweetheart.
-Mom, Dad.
- 안녕, 내 새끼
- 엄마
아버지
늦어서 미안하구나, 내가
'튜브'를 타자고 하는 바람에
Sorry we're late.
My fault.
I insisted on riding the tube.
여보, 애들 앞에서
Judy, the kids!
당신도 참, 여기선
지하철을 그렇게 불러요
Jack, that's what they call the subway.
저런, 난...
-I thought
-Dad, we got it.
- 아버지, 알았어요
- 그만하세요
Here comes my dad and stepmom.
저희 부모님이 오시네요
Mr. and Mrs. Geller.
아버님, 어머님?
-This is Steven...
-Hello, darling.
이 분은 스티븐 월섬...
...and Andrea Waltham.
그리고 안드레아 월섬
안녕하세요
반갑습니다
Very nice to meet you.
Darling, the Gellers.
여보, 겔러 부부시래
Darling, it's the Gellers.
겔러 부부시라니까
She's very self-involved.
I should never have married her.
자기밖에 모르는 여자죠
결혼한 게 후회막급입니다
뭐라구요?
-It's the Gellers.
-Where?
- 겔러 부부셔
- 누가요?
That's one and that's another one.
이쪽 양반하고
저쪽 여사
Lovely to meet you.
정말 반가워요
Nice of you to offer to pay
for half the wedding.
혼인비용을 절반이나
부담하신다니 고맙습니다
The hell with tradition.
We're happy to do it.
격식 따져서 뭐하나요
마음 쓰지 마세요
혼인에 들어가는 돈이
어디 한두 푼인가요
We know how expensive
weddings can be.
Besides, this may be
the only wedding we get to throw.
게다가 이제 집안에
혼사는 없을 듯해서
세계 어디서나 통하는 조크죠
A joke that's funny in all countries.
Sir?
선생님?
-What's in it?
-Goat cheese, watercress and pancetta.
뭐가 들었죠?
고트치즈와 물냉이
삼겹살입니다
That's not food.
그게 먹는 건가요?
난 됐어요
Everything's different here.
I want to go home.
여긴 모든 게 달라
난 집에 갈래
가족도 그립고
커피하우스도 그리워
I miss my family, the coffeehouse.
I can't even remember
what Phoebe looks like!
피비 얼굴도 까먹었어
It's been three days.
겨우 사흘이야
Okay, you're just homesick.
알아? 가벼운 향수병이라고
편안하게 이 순간을 즐겨봐
Would you just try to relax
and just enjoy yourself?
You're different here too.
너도 달라졌구나
You're mean in England!
영국 와서 성격 버렸어
What the hell?
- 이게 뭐야
- 왜 그러세요?
What's up, Dad?
This bill for my half of the wedding.
It's insane.
내가 부담하는 게
터무니없이 많잖아
피로연도 집에서 하는데
어떻게 된 거죠?
How can it be so much?
The reception's at their house.
Flowers, liquor.
Re-carpet first floor?
꽃에다 술에다
1층 카펫 다시 깔고
내빈용 욕조
조경공사
New guest bath, landscaping.
I'm paying to remodel this guy's house.
아주 집을 다시 지어라
이 자식이 누굴 호구로 보나
I'm gonna give that son of a bitch
a piece of my mind.
아버지, 제발 앉으세요
Please.
I don't want anything
to upset Emily tonight.
에밀리 기분도 생각해주세요
안 그래도 요즘 힘들었어요
She's had a hard enough
couple of days as it is.
제가 가서 얘기할게요, 됐죠?
Here.
Let me go talk to him.
You tell him no one takes advantage
of the Gellers.
겔러 집안을 우습게 보면
큰코다친다고 전해
어머나, 잭...
Sometimes I forget
how powerful you can be.
가끔 보면 당신 너무 듬직해
And I'm gonna go get drunk.
난 술이나 부어보자
- 안녕하세요
- 어서 오세요
-Hello.
반가워요
When is your next
flight to London?
다음 런던행이 몇 시죠?
There's one leaving in 30 minutes.
30분 후에 이륙합니다
And I do have one seat left.
좌석이 딱 하나 남았군요
정말 다행이네요
Thank you, thank you.
출발 전 요금은
2,700달러입니다
The last-minute fare
on this ticket is $2700.
Huh. How about 600?
600달러는 어때요
-Sorry.
-How about 600 and these earrings?
죄송합니다
600달러에다 이 귀고리
They prefer it if I don't barter.
물물교환은 곤란한데요
I don't think I have enough left
on my credit card.
신용카드 잔고가 부족해요
다른 카드로 나눠 내세요
You can split it with another card.
How about five?
다섯 개도 괜찮을까요?
고마워요
Thank you.
여권을 제시해주시죠
I'm just going to need
to see your passport.
I don't have it, but I can tell you
exactly where it is on my nightstand.
제가 그걸 침대 옆
테이블에 두고 왔는데...
대신 운전면허증도 있고
You know what?
I have my driver's license.
또 20달러도 있군요
And I have a 20.
Face it. My father is not going to pay
for the built-in barbecue.
붙박이 바비큐 시설은
해드릴 수가 없습니다
And believe me, you can
kiss your gazebo goodbye.
전망대도 애초에 포기하세요
I might be able
to get you the new lawn.
마당 잔디는 새로
깔 수 있을 겁니다
그럼 마당에 놓을
장식품도 필요한데
Then you have to give us
the lawn ornaments.
I go back there with lawn ornaments,
he'll laugh in my face.
그 얘기 꺼냈다간
아버지한테 맞아죽어요
This is ridiculous.
I mean, we had an agreement.
합의해놓고 이럼 어떡하나
Will you say something, Steven?
당신은 입이 붙었어요?
Don't take that tone with me.
이 사람이 어따 대고
알았어, 맘대로 해
All right, you can.
안녕, 피비
오, 살았다
마음을 바꿨구나
Thank God!
You changed your mind.
혼자 있고 싶으면 그렇게 해
어쨌든 너 생각 잘한 거야
You probably want to be alone,
you don't want to talk about it.
You're doing the right thing.
- 잘 있어, 피비
- 잠깐, 어디 가
Where are you going?
무슨 짓이야, 기다려
What are you doing? No, wait.
쟤 달아날 때마다
웬 몸이 이리 무거워
Why am I always pregnant
when she does that?
I'd like to make a toast
to Ross and Emily.
로스와 에밀리를 위해
건배하고 싶군요
My big toast is tomorrow.
본격적인 건배는 내일로 미루고
약식건배... 약밥건배로 나가죠
This is kind of my little toast,
or Melba toast, if you will.
좋습니다
Okay.
I've known Ross for a long time. I knew him
when he was with his first girlfriend.
로스와 전 오랜 친구로서
첫 데이트상대도 알고 있는데
I thought things were going to work out
for him, until the day he over-inflated her.
로스가 너무 띄워주는 통에
간이 부어서 떠나버리더군요
Oh, dear God!
주여, 굽어살피소서
Hello, Waltham lnteriors.
월섬 인테리어입니다
Mrs. Waltham.
네, 월섬 부인? 신랑들러리나
모니카랑 통화했으면 하는데
I need to speak with one of the best men
or Ross' sister, Monica.
-Who is this?
-Phoebe, one of Ross' best friends.
누구죠?
피비 부페이라고
로스의 친구랍니다
How did you get this number?
이 번호는 어떻게 알았죠?
I got it from your maid.
She's a bitch, but I wore her down.
가정부가 가르쳐주더군요
망할 년이라 살짝 밟아줬죠
로스의 친구라면
왜 안 온 거죠?
If you're one of Ross' best friends,
why aren't you here?
남동생의 아이를 가져서
비행기를 못 타거든요
I can't fly.
I'm having my brother's babies.
Am I on the radio?
제가 라디오에 출연했나요?
아뇨, 좀 바꿔주세요
아주 중요한 일이에요
Can I talk to one of them?
It's important.
I'm bored of you now.
I'm going to cut you off.
싱거워라
이만 끊읍시다
Oh, okay, I'm going
to have to kick her ass too.
이 여자 엉덩짝도 봐줘야겠다
We're excited that Ross and Emily are
getting married at Montgomery Hall.
모두 가슴이 벅찰 겁니다
몽고메리 홀에서
식을 올리게 되다니
To think, my friend getting
married in Monty Hall.
몬티 홀에서 결혼한다네요
Come on, Monty Hall!
몬티 홀이라구요!
사람 하나 살려봅시다!
Let's Make a Deal.
Come on, you people!
All right, forget it.
Congratulations, Ross and Emily.
됐어요, 결혼 축하한다
여러분, 2번 신랑들러리
조이 트리비아니입니다
Best man number two, Joey Tribbiani.
I'm not good with the jokes
like Chandler here.
전 챈들러처럼 농담은
잘 못하지만...
행복한 커플에게
축하를 보내고 싶군요
Congratulations to the happy couple.
I first met Ross
in this coffeehouse back home.
로스를 처음 만난 곳은
고향의 커피하우스였죠
Home.
고향
New York City.
뉴욕 시
Where everybody knows my name.
모두가 날 아는 동네
Anyway...
어쨌거나...
두 사람을 사랑한다
...I love you guys.
But not as much as I love America.
미국만큼 사랑하진 않지만
Can we please go home now?
이제 집에 가도 되지?
Are you going home?
집에 가시게요?
당신에 대해 궁금한 게 많은데
I was hoping to get
to know you better.
I'm not going anywhere, sweetheart.
가긴 어딜 가겠습니까
I was laughing.
난 웃었어
Out loud?
소리 내서?
I didn't want everyone
to think I was stupid.
그럼 날 바보로 알잖아
So how are you?
기분은 어때?
My mother's driving me crazy.
But Ross is getting married. I'm happy.
엄마 때문에 미치겠지만
오빠가 결혼한다니 기뻐
이 기분 망치긴 싫어
I'm not going to let anything spoil that.
I just want to say that
Ross is a wonderful young man.
로스는 정말 훌륭한 청년이오
감사합니다
우리도 좋아해요
Thanks. We like him.
My God! You must have been
a teenager when you had him.
맙소사, 10대에
로스를 낳았나보군요
There's no way in hell
I'm paying for it.
난 절대 그 돈 못 내놓겠소
Look, we're down to just one point.
제 부탁 하나만 들어주세요
결혼식 끝난 다음에 해결해요
Could we please just settle it
after the wedding?
Fine, but I'm not paying
for your wine cellar...
알았다, 하지만 포도주
저장실은 못 지어줘
...you thieving, would-be-speaking-
German-if-it-weren't-for-us, cheap little man!
벼룩의 간을 내먹을
날강도 같은 양반아
The guy was hammered. There's
no way you look like Ross' mother.
술 취한 사람이잖아
네가 어딜 봐서 로스 엄마야
-Then why would he say it?
-Because he's crazy!
- 그럼 왜 그런 말을 해
- 정신이 없으니까
He came up to me earlier and thanked me
for my very moving performance in Titanic.
아까는 '타이타닉'에서
내 연기가 너무 감동적이래
My mother's right.
I'll never get married.
엄마 말이 맞아
난 결혼 못할 거야
You know what, that is
왜 이래...
Who wouldn't want you?
누가 널 마다하겠니
Please! I'm a single mom
with a 30-year-old son.
난 30살 짜리 아들을
홀로 키우는 미혼모야
-Hi, I'm back. Listen, I need to
-Hello.
나 또 왔어요
- 저기...
- 어서 오세요
Hello. I need to get on that 11:00 flight.
네, 11시 비행기
꼭 타야 되는데
벌써 게이트와 분리됐답니다
I'm afraid that plane's already
pulled away from the gate.
당장 비행기 돌려서
날 태우라고 하세요
You're going to have to call that plane and
tell them to swing around and pick me up.
-Can't do that.
-Sure, you know what?
그건 불가능하죠
갑자기 문제가 생겼다고
하는 거예요, 엔진고장
We'll just tell them that there was, like,
a problem with, like, the engine.
I'm afraid I'm going to have
to ask you to step aside, miss.
죄송하지만 옆으로
비켜서 주시죠
Look, if I don't get to London
he is gonna marry that other girl.
내가 런던에 못 가면
딴 여자가 신부 된다구요
Can't imagine why.
그럴 만도 하네
All right. You know what?
좋아요, 비행기 돌릴 때까지
여기서 꼼짝도 안 할 거예요
I am not leaving here until
you call that plane back.
자리 비움
I'm getting married today!
나 오늘 결혼한다!
Morning.
- 잘 잤니?
- 나 오늘 결혼한다!
-I'm getting married today!
-Yeah, you are.
- 맞아!
- 아비요!
못 봤겠지?
Do you think he knew I was here?
-Excuse me.
-Yeah.
- 저 좀 볼까요?
- 네
If you're going to do that
throughout the flight, tell me now...
계속 그럴 거면 미리 말해줘요
수면제 한 알 먹게
...so that I can take a sedative.
Or perhaps slip you one.
아가씨가 먹든지
I'm sorry. I'm very sorry. Sorry.
죄송해요, 사과드릴게요
It's just, I'm kind of excited.
사실 좀 흥분이 돼서요
I'm going to London...
런던에 사랑을 고백하러
가는 길이거든요
...to tell this guy that I love him.
Well, I've never done that with you before.
너랑은 이게 처음이지?
맞아
기분은 좀 어때
뭣이냐... 괜찮아?
So how are you?
You okay?
Yeah. Yeah. You?
- 그래, 넌?
- 좋지 뭐, 어허?
Oh, yes. Yes.
You?
넌?
We did you.
서로 물어봤구나
Well....
그럼...
-I better get going.
-Absolutely.
- 가봐야겠다
- 그래, 당연하지
Could you not look?
보지 말래?
I don't want to look.
보고 싶지 않아
여보세요?
Where the hell have you been?
야, 너 어디 갔었어
너구나, 지금 들어왔다
신부들러리를 만났는데
I spent the night out.
I met this cute bridesmaid. She is so
- 얼마나 귀여운지...
- 듣고 싶지 않아
I don't want to hear it!
Pheebs, you know you're still
my number-one girl.
그래도 아직은 네가 최고야
No. No. We have an emergency.
Rachel's coming to London.
그게 아니라 사고 터졌다
레이첼이 런던으로 갔어
잘됐네
Great!
잘되다니, 로스한테 가서
사랑한다는 말을 하겠대
No, it's not great. She's coming
to tell Ross that she loves him.
로스는 에밀리를 사랑하잖아
But he loves Emily.
나도 알아
I know that!
You have to stop her.
She's going to ruin the wedding.
걔 막지 못하면
결혼식 망칠 거야
Okay.
알았어
-All right, so
-Hold on, hold on.
- 잘 들어
- 잠깐만...
Rachel coming.
레이첼이 온다
Do...
조치를...
...something.
취하라
내가 할 일은 다했어
I've done my part, okay?
이젠 너희들 몫이야
난 책임 없다, 알았지?
It's your responsibility now.
The burden is off me.
-Right?
-Right.
그래
So tell me about this girl.
그 여자가 어쨌다고?
And so then I realized,
all the stuff that I had been doing...
내 행동이 모두
잘못된 거였어요
...proposing to Joshua, lying to Ross about
why I couldn't come to the wedding...
조슈아한테 청혼하고 바쁘단
핑계로 결혼식에 안 가고...
-...was all just a way
-Oh, oh, oh, oh!
I'm sorry, can I interrupt?
미안하지만 한 마디 할까요?
I just want to say that you are
a horrible, horrible person.
당신 진짜 상종 못할 여자군요
Pardon me?
뭐라구요?
사랑하는 남자의 가장 행복한
날을 망치겠다는 심산이잖소
You say you love this man, and yet you're
about to ruin the happiest day of his life.
I'm afraid I have to agree
with your friend Pheebs.
피비라는 친구 말이 백 번 맞지
This is a terrible, terrible plan.
이건 사람이 할 짓이 못돼요
-But he has to know how I feel.
-But why?
내 감정은 알려야죠
왜요?
He loves this Emily person.
No good can come of this.
남자는 에밀리를 사랑하는데
알려서 좋을 게 뭐가 있소
-Well, I think you're wrong.
-Oh, no.
아저씨가 틀렸어요
그러쇼?
Well, he doesn't really love her.
It's just a rebound thing from me.
진정한 사랑이 아니라
나에 대한 반항심리예요
-You'll see.
-Fortunately I won't.
두고 봐요
다행히 못 볼 거요
And by the way, it seems to be
perfectly clear that you were on a break.
두 사람이 깨졌던 건
명백한 사실이구만 뭐
Do something.
조치를 취하라
Something.
조치라...
야
- 너 모니카 봤냐?
- 누가 모니카를 만나
-Have you seen Monica?
-I'm not seeing Monica!
-What?
- 뭐?
- 뭘?
We gotta find her. Rachel's coming
to tell Ross she loves him.
찾아야 돼, 레이첼이 여기 와서
로스를 사랑한다고 말할 거래
-Oh, my God!
-I know. Do you know where Monica is?
일났네
그래서 모니카를 찾아야 돼
어디 있는지 알아?
모른다니까 왜 이래
차라리 물고문을 해라
No. What's with the third degree?
Why not just shine a light in my eyes?
Oh, my God!
어머나, 세상에
요정 나라 같아요
It's like a fairyland.
I know. It's horrible, isn't it?
네, 정말 끔찍하죠?
I love it. I only hope
my wedding looks this good.
전 좋은데요?
내 결혼식도 이랬으면
-I just hope
-You can let some of them go by.
- 그럼 내 손에 장을...
- 한 번쯤은 참아주세요
모니카
Start looking out for Rachel.
레이첼을 찾아야 돼
I'll cover the front door.
You watch that big hole.
난 정문을 맡을게
넌 건물 뒤의 구멍을 감시해
And I got Chandler covering Ross.
챈들러는 로스를 보호할 거야
챈들러가 뭘 하든 알 게 뭐야
Why would I care where Chandler is?
You know...
그니까...
...sometimes I don't even
like Chandler.
가끔은 챈들러가 싫어
Okay.
알았다
I do.
네, 네...
네
-You're right. It's the second one.
-Right?
- 역시 두 번째 게 좋다
- 그치?
Hello, Joey.
안녕, 조이
펠리시티
Hey, Felicity.
종일 자기 생각했어
I thought about you all day.
그래?
Talk New York to me again.
뉴욕 사투리 또 들려줘
Forget about it.
뭘 또 새삼스럽게
How you doing?
안녕하쇼
포도주 저장실은
안 된다고 했잖아요
There's nothing to discuss.
We're not paying for your wine cellar.
절반씩 부담하는 거잖소
You have to meet me in the middle here.
그러다 엉덩이 절반으로
쪼개지는 수가 있어
My foot's gonna meet
the middle of your ass.
무슨 일이에요
-What's going on?
-Everything's under control.
괜찮아, 내가 처리할게
지금 나랑 한번
붙어보자 이거요?
You want a piece of me, sir?
Is that what you're saying?
됐어요, 그만!
다들 물러서세요!
That's it! Parents! Parents!
Back away!
This is our wedding day!
오늘은 결혼식이에요
From now on, everyone gets along.
이제 싸움은 그만두세요
한마디만 더 들리면...
And if I hear one more word...
...no grandchildren!
That's right!
손주는 없어요, 아셨죠!
-Okay, okay.
-Sorry, old boy.
알았다
미안하네
I could kill you
with my thumb, you know.
한 주먹감도 안 되는 게
What was all that about?
이게 무슨 일이야?
It was this disagreement over
그냥 의견충돌이지 뭐...
자기 정말 예쁘다
My God! You look beautiful.
You're not meant to see me
before the wedding. It's bad luck.
예식 전에 신부를 보면
불운이 찾아온대
I think we've had all the bad luck
we're going to have.
불운은 이미 겪을 만큼 겪었어
My God, Rachel!
세상에, 레이첼
You're here.
I can't believe it.
와줬구나
믿어지지 않아
What happened?
Why are you here?
무슨 일이야
왜 왔어
그냥...
I just came to
I just needed to tell you...
할말이 있어서
...congratulations.
결혼 축하해
Hello, Waltham lnteriors.
월섬 인테리어입니다
Mrs. Waltham? It's Phoebe.
월섬 부인
또 저예요, 피비
Why?
왜요
Can I talk to one of the best men?
This is going to be the last time.
제발 들러리 좀 바꿔주세요
이번이 진짜 마지막이에요
There's a girl on the phone for you.
조이, 여자 전화예요
Great!
좋죠
여보세요?
It's Phoebe.
조이, 나 피비야
레이첼 막았어?
Did you stop Rachel?
No, but it's okay. She just came in
and gave him a hug. That's it.
아니, 괜찮아
그냥 껴안고 끝났어
-Nothing got ruined?
-No.
사고 안 쳤어?
그럼
That's so great!
정말 다행이다
So, what's going on now?
어떻게 돼가?
식장에 들어가는 중이야
I'm walking down the aisle.
Still walking.
아직 걷고 있어
I'm about to pass the bridesmaid
I hooked up with last night.
어제 만났던
신부들러리 앞이야
Hey.
안녕?
I just told her "hey."
방금 인사했다
이제 로스 옆에 섰어
피비야
I'm at the front with Ross.
It's Phoebe!
화난 것 같다
He looks pretty mad.
I better go.
끊을게
안돼, 끊지 마
듣고 싶어
Wait! Hold it up so I can listen.
-What we did last night was
-Stupid.
- 어젯밤 일은...
- 바보짓이었어
맞아, 정신 나간 짓이었지
Totally crazy, stupid.
What were we thinking?
무슨 생각으로 그랬을까
I'm coming over
tonight though, right?
오늘밤에 가도 되지?
Definitely.
당연한 걸 묻네
Friends, family...
오늘 여러분께서는
...we are gathered to celebrate...
로스와 에밀리의 복된 결합을
축하하기 위해 여기 모였습니다
...the joyous union
of Ross and Emily.
이 날의 기쁨이 두 사람과
영원히 함께 하길 빌며...
May the happiness of today...
...be with them always.
Now, Emily, repeat after me.
에밀리, 날 따라하세요
나 에밀리는
-l, Emily...
이 사람 로스를
-...take thee, Ross...
-...take thee, Ross....
이 사람 로스를
생사고락을 같이할 합법적인
남편으로 맞이하겠습니다
...as my lawfully wedded husband,
in sickness and in health...
...till death parts us.
생사고락을 같이할 합법적인
남편으로 맞이하겠습니다
As my lawfully wedded husband,
in sickness and in health...
...until death parts us.
Now, Ross.
이제 로스
날 따라하세요
Repeat after me.
I, Ross...
나 로스는
...take thee, Emily...
이 사람 에밀리를
...take thee, Rachel
이 사람 레이첼을
Emily.
에밀리를
에, 에밀리를
Emily.
Shall I go on?
계속해도 될까요?
"Mother, Mother, Pizza, Pizza," take one.
Oh, the band's ready?
We gotta do what the band says, right?
I don't care about the stupid band!
-Well, it's getting late.
-Here we go.
Actually, you guys mind staying here
with me for a while?
You know, we gotta get up early
and catch the plane to New York.
Yeah, it's a very large plane.
Why, what's the matter?